ANFAAL FAISAL

Kalamazoo, MI 49006 (346) 204-1630 - afjdeveloper@gmail.com

Website: https://afaisal.dev/

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Goal-oriented Web Developer with strong commitment to collaboration and solutions-oriented problem-solving. Use various web design software to develop customer-focused websites and designs. Committed to high standards of web design, user experience, usability and speed for multiple types of end-users. Successful at maintaining customer satisfaction through effective customer support.

EDUCATION

Expected in 12/2021 Bachelor of Science: Computer Science

Western Michigan University - Kalamazoo, MI

06/2016 High School Diploma

Wesgreen International School - Dubai

WORK HISTORY

12/2018 to Current

Help Desk Student Lead

WMU Office Of Information And Technology – Kalamazoo, MI

- Trained and supported end-users with software, hardware and network standards and use processes
- Monitored problem management database and followed up with assigned personnel
- Followed up with clients to verify optimal customer satisfaction following support engagement and problem resolution
- Scheduled staff and delivered training materials and information
- Patched software and installed new versions to eliminate security problems and protect data
- DUPE Engaged end-users and answered questions via email, phone, website live chat and in forums
- Removed malware, ransomware and other threats from laptops and desktop systems
- Resolved conflicts and negotiated mutually beneficial agreements between parties
- Worked with students/staff customers to understand needs and provide technical service

08/2018 to 02/2019 Alumni Ambassador

WMU Alumni Association – Kalamazoo, MI

- Maintained excellent attendance record, consistently arriving to work on time
- Increased customer satisfaction by resolving donation issues
- Developed team communications and information for team meetings

08/2018 to 01/2019 **Server**

WMU Catering – Kalmazoo, MI

• Collaborated with kitchen team to support order preparation, manage efficient deliveries and minimize customer service issues by verifying meals

06/2018 to 07/2018 Project Management Intern

Rexel Middle East – Dubai, United Arab Emirates

- Attended Health Safety and Environmental (HSE) training conducted by Chicago Bridge and Iron (CB&I) (McDermott) for their ongoing plastic factory project in Oman (Sohar)
- Supported project managers in managing schedules and milestones
- Coordinated internal resources and third-party vendors for flawless execution of projects
- Tracked project performance to analyze successful completion of short- and long-term goals
- Identified project scopes, constraints, risks and deadlines

ACCOMPLISHMENTS

- WMU Racquetball Club E-board 2019-2020 Media Coordinator
- AUSMUN 2018 Secretariat of Human Rights Commission
- THIMUN Qatar 2015 Best Delegate Award in Human Rights Council
- DIFC Stock Market Simulation 2013 Top 50
- Murdoch University Business Cup 2015 3rd place (Best Case Study)

SKILLS

• AngularJS

• SQL

• HTML5

• Hypertext Preprocessor

JavaScript

JQuery

Java

• Python

• JSON

Software Development